<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gradle on Vinnie&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/gradle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gradle on Vinnie&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/gradle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a web application with Gretty, Cucumber and Selenium</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2014-09-03-testing-a-web-application-with-gretty-cucumber-and-selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2014-09-03-testing-a-web-application-with-gretty-cucumber-and-selenium/</guid>
      <description>The code used in this post is a complete web application built with Spring WebMVC, Spring Data and Spring Security. It contains a lot more than what is explained here and I hope to come back to it in later posts. The code can be found in my Github repository.
For this post I&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on how you can test a web application using Cucumber and Selenium. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using the Gretty plugin to start a web container during the build.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building with Gradle</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2014-05-18-building-with-gradle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2014-05-18-building-with-gradle/</guid>
      <description>Gradle is a build system that was build from the lessons learned from Ant and Maven. Similarly with Ant, where you have a XML namespace to write build scripts, Gradle is a DSL on top of Groovy that helps you write build scripts. But it goes further with many plugins and conventions (like Maven) that make it possible to get a build up and running with just a few lines of Groovy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build tools for Java</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2013-12-17-build-tools-for-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2013-12-17-build-tools-for-java/</guid>
      <description>More than a year ago I wrote a post about how I started to use Maven to build my Java applications and how much I loved it! Things changed a lot since then and I, like many others, am moving my projects to Gradle. In this post - and a few more to come - I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about build tools for Java and make some comparisons and explain why I moved to Gradle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>