<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spring on Vinnie&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/spring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in spring on Vinnie&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/spring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SPA with Spring Boot</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2018-01-17-spa-with-spring-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2018-01-17-spa-with-spring-boot/</guid>
      <description>Single page applications are becoming more and more common these days. If you work with Spring Boot and want to build your frontend using this architecture, you have two options: build the frontend on a separate repository and serve it using some HTTP server or serve your files from your Java application.
This post explains the basic configuration needed so that you can manage routing on the frontend and still serve your static files from your Java/Spring application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Caching with Spring</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-07-22-simple-caching-with-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-07-22-simple-caching-with-spring/</guid>
      <description>This week an old friend contacted me because he was having memory problems in one of his applications. The problem was very simple: for each user logged in, all application menus and part of the list/combo values were being added to the user session (including some images). That was used to makes things faster, to avoid going to the database multiple times and loading the data all over again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Spring Security</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-07-20-customizing-spring-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-07-20-customizing-spring-security/</guid>
      <description>Spring Security is a very powerful and customizable security framework for JEE applications. This post will show how to integrate it seamlessly with your application setting up a custom login and logout.
You&amp;rsquo;ll also learn how to add a custom filter with very specific behavior and how to integrate with Spring Data so that your users can be loaded from a repository and avoid all the hassle of dealing with JDBC or Hibernate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bean Validation (JSR-303) and Spring MVC</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-04-14-bean-validation-jsr-303-and-spring-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-04-14-bean-validation-jsr-303-and-spring-mvc/</guid>
      <description>The code for this example can be found at the blog repository in github.
Validation in web applications normally spread through many lines of code in the client side and in the server side. JSR-303, or Bean Validation, is a standard developed to be part of JPA. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple and generic way to annotate your entities with specific validation rules and have them validated by some validation engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is and how to use @ModelAttribute</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-04-11-what-is-and-how-to-use-modelattribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-04-11-what-is-and-how-to-use-modelattribute/</guid>
      <description>You can get the code for this post in the blog repository in github.
Spring MVC is one of the easiest and most powerful MVC framework to build web applications in Java. With all the features that it has available it is impossible to know everything. But in most cases, when you ask the question: &amp;ldquo;Can Spring MVC do [put something complex and unexpected here]?&amp;rdquo; the answer is yes. And when it can&amp;rsquo;t, the answer is: it has a place for you to hook your code in and do whatever you need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Spring Data Example</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-03-26-simple-spring-data-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-03-26-simple-spring-data-example/</guid>
      <description>As my first post I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a very simple command line application that manages one entity called Person. The purpose of this example is to demonstrate how powerful the new Spring Data projects family are.
Spring Data Spring Data is a family of projects that aims to create a repository layer. The idea is to have an abstract layer were all the dependencies will point to and different implementations with all kinds of data repositories (SQL and NoSQL), similiar to what JDBC did for SQL databases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>